Within the experiment type of study,
实验型研究
there are different types of experiments.
包含不同类型的实验
In this video, we will study some of them.
在本视频中 我们将讲解其中一些类型
Let's take another look at the earlier example regarding the online store.
再来看看之前的在线商店示例
There, we wanted to test the effects of adding
之前 我们想测试下 当用户搜索之后点击商品图片
a summary overlay when a user clicks on a product image following a search.
如果出现摘要叠加页面 效果如何
The experimental setup that we had there was an example of an A/B test.
这种实验属于 A/B 测试
For each customer, we roll a die.
对于每个客户 我们都投掷一次骰子
If it's even, the customer gets put into group a.
如果是偶数 则将客户放入 A 组内
These participants won't see any changes.
这组参与者不会看到任何变化
They'll still see the old product results without any Quick View overlay.
依然看到旧版商品结果 没有快览叠加页面
Participants in group A are part of the control group.
A 组中的参与者属于对照组
On the other hand, if the roll is odd,
另一方面 如果骰子的读数是奇数
the customer will go into group B.
则将客户分配到 B 组中
This group will see the website changes and be able to see
这组客户将看到网站变化
the Quick View for any product returned from a search.
点击搜索到的任何商品都会看到快览叠加页面
Participants in group B will be part of the experimental group.
B 组中的参与者属于实验组
Once we've collected all of our data,
收集所有数据后
we can make an inference on the overlay by comparing the purchases on
我们将比较 B 组中的用户在新网站上的购买行为
the new website in group B to the purchases on the old website in group A.
与 A 组中的用户在旧网站上的购买行为 进而推断叠加页面的效果
The A/B test I just described is also an example of a between-subjects design.
我刚刚描述的 A/B 测试属于一种组间设计
In an experiment of this type,
在这种类型的实验中
each person only participates in one condition.
每个参与者只能参与一种情形
For the website example,
对于刚刚的网站示例来说
customers only see site A or site B, but never both.
客户只能看到网站 A 或网站 B 不能同时看到
In contrast, we can use an experiment type where
相反 还有一种实验
participants go through all of the experiment conditions.
参与者能够参与所有情形
This is called a within-subjects design.
称之为组内设计
For example, let's say we wanted to conduct a taste test between two soft drink formulas.
例如 假设我们想要测试两种软饮料配方的口味
As a between-subjects experiment,
在组间实验中
each participant would simply be randomized to rate either formula A or formula B alone.
每个参与者只能随机地对配方 A 或配方 B 打分
If we make this A within-subjects design instead,
如果是组内设计
each participant would then rate both formulas,
那么每个参与者都能对两种配方打分
either A then B or B then A.
可以先品尝 A 然后品尝 B 或先品尝 B 然后品尝 A
The benefit of this kind of design is that we can
这种设计的优势是
account for each individual's overall taste.
我们能考虑每位参与者的整体口味喜好
If a person only tasted formula A and gave it a rating of eight,
如果参与者只品尝了配方 A 并给出 8 分
we wouldn't necessarily know what part of that was due to
那么我们并不知道对于这个评分 有多少成分受到
the person's general inclinations toward soda and what part was due to the soda formula.
此人对苏打水的整体喜好程度的影响
Having that person make an additional rating on
让此人继续对 B 打分
B allows us to account for that person's full preferences,
可以告诉我们此人对苏打水的整体喜好程度
reducing the variance in the data to be analyzed.
这样可以降低数据的偏差
However, it's not always possible to run a within-subjects design.
但是 有时候无法实施组内设计
If you consider the earlier example for the shopping website,
对于之前的购物网站示例
there's no good way of requiring a shopper to see both versions of the site.
没有什么好的方法能够让购物者查看两个版本的网站
Once the shopper has made a purchase,
购物者购买商品后
there is no way to turn back time and have them make
我们无法让购物者再回到另一个版本的网站
the same purchase again in the version that they didn't see.
并购买相同的商品
There's also no guarantee that they'll come back
并且无法保证他们能快速返回
soon enough to give them the other version of the site.
并向他们显示另一个版本的网站
Of course, it doesn't make sense to randomly have both versions in the same session.
当然 在同一会话中随机地分配两个版本并不合理
In both of the examples,
在这两个示例中
we split people up among two conditions: the two
我们都在两个情形间分配了参与者
different website flows or the two different soda formulas.
即两种不同的网站流程或两种不同的苏打水配方
But it's also possible to create designs where you might have more conditions.
但是我们还可以设计包含更多情形的实验
For example, one control group and two experimental groups.
例如一个对照组和两个实验组
There are also designs where you collect data in different ways.
还可以通过不同的方式收集数据
You can see more about these other experimental designs below.
你可以在视频下方详细了解其他实验设计